# DINH TAN (TOMMY)

# **NGUYEN**

0451 549 868

tommyfederation@gmail.com

linkedin.com/in/tommy-ngx

in



# A BRIEF OF ME

I am a business person and a technology generalist with a specialization in data science & statistics. I am keenly interested in changes to the technological, financial and administrative landscape; & passionate about the ever-evolving fields of technology & data science & how their applications can increase profits.



# **RESEARCH INTERESTS**

- Data Science
- Privacy Protection
- Business Intelligence
- Automation Administration

- Al, Data Analytic
- Financial Accounting, Economics

MAR 2016 – MAR 2018

JAN 2014 - JAN 2016

GPA: 5.917 / 7

GPA: 5.250 / 7

- Machine Learning (Deep Learning)
- Fintech



# **EDUCATION**

**Master of Technology (Software Engineering)** FEDERATION UNIVERSITY (SYDNEY CAMPUS)

FINAL PROJECT (High Distinction): Develop a Market place for selling study materials by Students.

Supervised by: Dr. Sanjay Jha

**Master of Business Administration** 

WESTERN SYDNEY UNIVERSITY (SYDNEY CAMPUS)

FINAL PROJECT (Distinction): Addressing the faced issues of Vietnam Starbuck

Supervised by: Dr. Nicole Stegemann

**Bachelor of Financial Accounting** 

JUL 2008 - JUN 2012

DANANG UNIVERSITY OF ARCHITECTURE (DANANG CAMPUS) GPA: 8.04 / 10

Thesis Statement (High Distinction): Solution for improving competitive advantages of L/C (Letter of Credit) in Techcombank Danang.

Supervised by: Dr. Dang My Phuong Phan



# **RESEARCH EXPERIENCE**

Project: AIG Enterprise Project (Sydney)

# #commercial\_transfromation\_platform

- Supporting the Project team in with the monitoring and analysing of business readiness activities for each product launch.
- Assisting with onboarding activities to various business systems prior to each product launch
- Researching and tracking priority Defects and Incidents using AIG standard tools and processes
- Collecting data from defect, running meetings between project stakeholders, taking detailed minutes
- Tracking action points from meetings and escalating any that have not moved forward to the PC/PM
- Maintaining MS Project Plans, tracking key project work stream milestones and alerting the PC/PM when due dates are approaching, to ensure the schedule remains on track.

# Project: Allripe Website Development (Sydney) #web\_design\_layout\_database

- Developing and implementing project plan under the guidance of Project Manager to develop future capability and timely project delivery
- Researching, analysing and preparing options in relation to business cases, Evaluation and Negotiation Plans and project deliverables to guide optimal decision making within deadlines
- Developing and maintaining relationships with the client Sponsors to ensure project KPIs and organisational outcomes are achieved
- Giving presentation at meeting of 30 attendees
- Liaising with integrated stakeholders to prepare project documentations and ensure requests/enquiries are handled in timely and efficient manner

# Project: Traveling on Thung Boat (Danang)

# #reseach\_plan\_implement

- Facilitating group discussions or conduct meetings
- Identifying goals and/or tasks to be accomplished and a realistic timeline for completion
- Designing and analysing surveys, understand and synthesize all datasets.
- Developing organizing principles to effectively sort and evaluate data
- Working effectively under pressure and to meet deadlines



# **WORKING EXPERIENCE**

# Warehouse IT Technician | IT E-waste | Sydney city

## MAR 2019 – MAR 2020

- Maintaining and administering computer networks and related computing environments including computer hardware, systems software, applications software, and all configurations.
- Maintaining the operating systems in operational mode and escalate issues to appropriate level of support.
- Providing first level support with other staff regarding all IT issues to provide solution, both hardware and software, documenting all issues to company system and resolving all relevant issues.
- Carefully checking data security and doing data wiping, updating the latest version of software.
- Performing hardware maintenance on PC including: cleaning and testing warehouse label; cleaning and repairing warehouse workstations; completing assigned preventive maintenance tasks.
- Communicating with clients and providing customer services to fulfil all the requests and orders.

#### 

- Trained to be a Marketing Executive you will work across all facets of Emergency, share a responsibilities and tasks with a great team.
- Developed strategic relations to secure sponsorship to assist with the publicity and funding of marketing projects.
- Responsible for providing assistance to the Sales Manager
- Monitored new product market performance
- Training all office staff and salesmen in branch offices.
- Assistant for Regional Manager
- Building Company Profile and identifying Brands.
- Researched distributors and market as Customer Service Supervisor.

# Marketing Researcher | TNS Vietnam | Danang City

JUN 2010 - JUN 2011

- Finding a suitable Candidate based on survey and requested researches.
- Interviewing to get the useful Information, relied on sample, mean and selected target candidates.
- Collecting information on survey, filtering the wrong answers by direct and indirect questions.
- Reviewing and sorting Information, comparing the sample and report to manager with KPI.



# **AWARDS AND CERTIFICATES**

•	Golden Key International Honor Society – Federation University	2018
•	MIT Partner – Melbourne Institute of Technology	2016
•	Runner-up of Soft-skill Series Video – United States Consulate General	2014
•	Incentive awards of Social Venture Plan Contest – Seattle Pacific University	2011
•	Incentive awards of Creative Business Idea Contest – University of Danang	2010



# **MEMBERSHIP & SKILLS**

# **Membership of Australian Computer Society**

• #4174606

### **TECHNICAL SKILL**

- Expert user of Microsoft suite Excel, Word, PowerPoint and Outlook
- Competent at providing remote support, problem solving, troubleshooting with different internet browsers
- Operating systems: Workstations OS, Windows OS and Mac OS, Linux OS
- Language: HTML, PHP and SQL
- Server OS: Linux and Windows Server.
- Basic Java, Python, R.
- Adept experience in security software, virus scanning, installing antivirus system.
- Able to perform excellent IT asset management: desktops, laptops, tablets and smartphones ensuring up to date documentation and closure issues.

# **PERSONAL SKILL**

- Good communication skills, and a passion for customer service.
- An active and versatile team member
- Self-learning, quick learner.
- Online learning
- Remote working



# **REFERENCES**

# **Available on Request**